CA.OLIVEIRASILVA@HOTMAIL.COM





CDEOLIVEIRASILVA

LEIDEN, THE NETHERLANDS





+31 6 251 707 52



CDEOLIVEIRASILVA

FREELANCE TRANSLATOR, CONSULTANT & TRANSCRIBER

ABOUT

Multi-skilled and reliable translator and transcriber with almost 2 years of professional experience. An enthusiastic learner who's able to absorb new ideas, communicate clearly and effectively with people from all social, cultural and prefessional backgrounds. A linguist with a vast set of skills and a keen eye for detail, who always goes the extra mile. Interested in graphic and web design, web development, e-commerce, nutrition, fitness, nature and travelling.

EDUCATION

2014 - 2018

BACHELOR JAPANESE STUDIES

+ MINOR 'CULTURAL MEMORY OF WAR AND CONFLICT'. 2016 - 2017 LEIDEN UNIVERISTY

2007 - 2014

GYMNASIUM (E&M)

HET NIEUWE LYCEUM

LANGUAGES

Dutch

Native/bilingual profiency

Spanish

Japanese

English

Professional working profiency

Native/bilingual profiency

Limited working profiency

Brazilian Portuguese

Native/bilingual profiency

French

Limited working profiency

GRAPHIC DESIGN (INTERMEDIATE)









PROGRAMMING (INTERMEDIATE)















OFFICE & TRANSLATION (ADVANCED)











WORK EXPERIENCE

April 2020 - Present

SOEDESCO PUBLISHING BV

FREELANCE TRANSLATOR & CONSULTANT

I've recently resumed parts of my job at game publishing company SOEDESCO to help them translate and write documentation in Japanese for and handle the communication with age rating classification system (CERO).

November 2019 - Present

UPWORK & GOTRANSCRIPT

FREELANCE TRANSLATOR, CONSULTANT & TRANSCRIBER

As a freelancer, I provide translations to and from English, Dutch, Brazilian Portuguese and Japanese. Besides documents, I offer powerpoint slides to be used with international clients in the target language, company newsletters, emails or letters that need to be exchanged with international business partners, press releases and media kits geared towards industry press & general media about (new) product (re)releases. I also offer transcriptions for i.e. business meetings, conference (calls), e-courses, interviews, lectures, podcasts, video blogs and webcasts.

October 2019 - February 2020

TEMPER.WORKS

FLEXWORKER IN RETAIL & FOOD INDUSTRY

October 2018 - April 2019

SOEDESCO PUBLISHING BV

TERRITORY MANAGER FOR JAPANESE & SOUTH-AMERICAN MARKET

As territory manager at this videogame publisher, I was responsible for the translation and documentation process in Japanese for age rating classification (CERO). My other tasks included translating press releases to Japanese and Portuguese; translating and creating social media content for Japan and Brazil providing costumer support; handling communication and business in Japanese and Portuguese with potential/partner companies in those regions. Additional activities were i.e. game footage recording, game testing (QA) and localization check for multiple languages.

April 2017 - October 2018

VERSCENTRUM NEDERLAND BV

ORDERPICKER

May 2014 - May 2019

TAJI THE CHEF

PART-TIME ASSISTANT

June 2015 - February 2016 THUISZORGINHOLLAND BV

PART-TIME HOME CARE WORKER

RISTORANTE GASPARE, LA PLACE SCHIPHOL, MISE EN PLACE PART-TIME WAITRESS/BARTENDER

OTHER ACTIVITIES

April - June 2016

NISHINIHON INTERNATIONAL EDUCATION INSTITUTE 3 MONTH LANGUAGE UNIVERSITY EXCHANGE PROGRAM IN FUKUOKA, JAPAN

July 2016

CENTRO DE RECUPERAÇÃO DO LOBO IBÉRICO

VOLUNTEER AT WOLF PRESERVATION PROJECT IN MAFRA, PORTUGAL

July - August 2015

SEA TURTLE PROTECTION SOCIETY OF GREECE ARCHELON VOLUNTEER AT TURTLE PRESERVATION PROJECT IN ZAKYNTHOS. GREECE